Guide to the Chelsea Records
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- November 2007 Acquisition, 1985-2007; 4.04; (8 boxes)
  - Computer media and audiovisual media
    - Computer media
      - Saje Miriam Drev, 2007-genm-11959-0001; 1 (Box 52)
      - [no label information], 2007-genm-11959-0002; 1 (Box 52)
      - [no label information], 2007-genm-11959-0003; 1 (Box 52)
      - René Guy Cadou (Jones/Yeatts), 2007-genm-11959-0004; 1 (Box 52)
      - "Excerpts from Afraid of the Dark" by Alfred Clemente, 2007-genm-11959-0005; 1 (Box 52)
      - [no label information], 2007-genm-11959-0006; 1 (Box 52)
      - Dan Stryk poems, 2007-genm-11959-0007; 1 (Box 52)
      - Kercheval - 4 poems + bio WORD, 2007-genm-11959-0008; 1 (Box 52)
      - [no label information], 2007-genm-11959-0009; 1 (Box 52)
      - RABB "Dante's Anteroom", 2007-genm-11959-0010; 1 (Box 52)
      - [no label information], 2007-genm-11959-0011; 1 (Box 52)
      - John Staples, 2007-genm-11959-0012; 1 (Box 52)
      - [no label information], 2007-genm-11959-0013; 1 (Box 52)
      - [no label information], 2007-genm-11959-0014; 1 (Box 52)
      - CHELSEA 81 COVER, 2007-genm-11959-0015; 1 (Box 52)
      - [no label information], 2007-genm-11959-0016; 1 (Box 52)
      - Chelsea 81 PDF, 2007-genm-11959-0017; 1 (Box 52)
      - JOHN WHALEN CHELSEA - Accepted Poems 82/83 NOV '07, 2007-genm-11959-0018; 1 (Box 52)
      - Carrie Bennett, 2007-genm-11959-0019; 1 (Box 52)
      - R. Elliott poems & bio. thanks! "Los Mineros para Los Minerales" "R. Elliott" "Lord's Resistance Army" biography, 2007-genm-11959-0020; 1 (Box 52)
      - [no label information], 2007-genm-11959-0021; 1 (Box 52)
      - JAMES HOGGARD translations of poems by OSCAR HAHN St. John of the Cross LISTENS…DIAPERS + Shrouds Tailor's Shop, 2007-genm-11959-0022; 1 (Box 52)
      - ROBERT NAZARENE POEM + BIO, 2007-genm-11959-0023; 1 (Box 52)
      - Goodrich - Isla Vista, 2007-genm-11959-0024; 1 (Box 52)
      - [no label information], 2007-genm-11959-0025; 1 (Box 52)
      - Bar-Nadav Poem, 2007-genm-11959-0026; 1 (Box 52)
      - "Tiber" Ann Snodgrass, 2007-genm-11959-0027; 1 (Box 52)
      - Louis Bourgeois A Season in HELL, 2007-genm-11959-0028; 1 (Box 52)
      - Chelsea 82/83 Book Reviews, 2007-genm-11959-0029; 1 (Box 52)
      - Tryst R. Linney, 2007-genm-11959-0030; 1 (Box 52)
      - Valentina gnup 4 poems, 2007-genm-11959-0031; 1 (Box 52)
      - Randall Watson, 2007-genm-11959-0032; 1 (Box 52)
      - Rowan Ricardo Phillips Poems for Chelsea 82/83, 2007-genm-11959-0033; 1 (Box 52)
      - NED CONDINI Essay on Cap Tohi, 2007-genm-11959-0034; 1 (Box 52)
      - THE OLD TOWN by LUIGI FONTANELLA WORD, 2007-genm-11959-0035; 1 (Box 52)
    - Audiovisual media
      - Jackson, Laura (Riding). Essay read by Sona Raiziss, 1 audiocassette (Box 53)
- April 2008 Acquisition, 1996-2008; 1.63; (3 boxes)
  - Correspondence
    - Bourgeois, Louis, 2007-2008; 3 folders, including 1 3.5 inch disk (Box 54)
    - Unsorted, 2007-2008; 6 (Box 54)
  - Chelsea Editions Publications
    - Bertoldo, Roberto, editor. Alfredo de Palchi: la potenza della poesia, 2006-2007, undated; 3 (Box 54)
    - Betocchi, Carlo. Awakenings: Selected Poems 1932-1982 (translated by Ned Condini), 2006-2008; 3 (Box 54)
    - Buffoni, Franco. Wings: Selected Poems, 2000-2005 (translated by Emanuel di Pasquale), 2007-2008; 3 folders, including 1 3.5 inch disk and 4 CDs (Box 54)
    - Magrelli, Valerio. Instructions on How to Read a Newspaper and Other Poems (translated by by Riccardo Duranti, Anamaría Crowe Serrano, and Anthony Molino), 2006-2008, undated; 3 folders, including 1 CD (Box 55)
    - Tyrell, Michael. The Primal Scene, undated (Box 55)
  - Other Papers
    - Printed material, 1996 (Box 55)
    - Manuscripts removed from books (Box 55)
- September 2008 Acquisition, 2005-2008; 1.91; (4 boxes)
  - Correspondence
    - Di Pasquale, Emanuel, 2005-2008, undated (Box 57)
    - Unsorted, 2006-2008, undated; 6 (Box 57)
    - Unsorted, 2008, undated (Box 59)
  - Chelsea Issues
    - Chelsea 79 (2005), 1 CD
    - Chelsea 80 (2006), 1 folder, including 1 CD (Box 58)
    - Chelsea 82/83 (2007), 6 3.5 inch disks, 1 zip disk, and 28 CDs (Box 58)
  - Chelsea Editions Publications
    - Rankin, Rush. The Aesthetics of Flesh, 2006, undated (Box 58)
    - Rankin, Rush. In Theory (Box 59)
    - Rankin, Rush. The Logic of Lost Thoughts, 2005-2006, undated (Box 58)
  - Literary Prizes
    - Il premio de Palchi-Raiziss, 2008 (Box 59)
  - Other Papers
    - Manuscripts removed from books, 2006, undated (Box 58)
- April 2009 Acquisition, 1979-2009; 1.42; (3 boxes)
  - Correspondence
    - Unsorted, 1993-2009; 5 (Box 61)
  - Chelsea Issues
    - Chelsea 72 (2002) (contracts with contributors) (Box 61)
    - Chelsea 73 (2002) (contracts with contributors) (Box 61)
    - Chelsea 74 (2003) (contracts with contributors) (Box 61)
    - Chelsea 75 (2003) (contracts with contributors) (Box 61)
    - Chelsea 76 (2004) (contracts with contributors) (Box 61)
    - Chelsea 77 (2004) (contracts with contributors) (Box 61)
    - Chelsea 78 (2005) (contracts with contributors) (Box 61)
    - Chelsea 79 (2005) (contracts with contributors) (Box 61)
    - Chelsea 80 (2006) (contracts with contributors) (Box 61)
    - Chelsea 81 (2006) (contracts with contributors) (Box 61)
    - Chelsea 82/83 (2007) (contracts with contributors) (Box 61)
  - Other Writings
    - Rosselli, Amelia. Impromptu, 2008; 4 folders, including 1 CD (Box 61)
  - Other Papers
    - Advertisements ("Soliciting File"), 2001, undated (Box 61)
    - Advertisements, 2005-2006, undated (Box 61)
    - Copyright, 1979-2008, undated; 2 (Box 61)
    - Chelsea Logo, undated (Box 61)
    - Chelsea indexes, undated (Box 61)
    - Managing editor interns, 2003-2005, undated (Box 61)
    - Chelsea Associates board meeting minutes, 1997-2006 (Box 61)
    - Foerster, Richard ("Richard's Resignation"), 1997-2005; 3 (Box 61)
    - Foerster, Richard ("Chelsea Problems Resolved"), 2000-2001 (Box 61)
    - Printed material, 2008 (Box 61)
    - Printed material, 2003-2009; 3 folders, including 2 CDs (Box 62)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box 62)
- November 2009 Acquisition, 2002-2009; 1.21; (2 boxes)
  - Correspondence
    - Unsorted, 2008-2009; 4 folders, including 1 3.5 inch disk (Box 64)
  - Chelsea Editions Publications
    - Caddeo, Rinaldo. Siren's Song: Selected Poetry and Prose, 1989-2009 (translated by Adria Bernardi), 11 folders, including 1 CD (Box 64)
    - Ferramosca, Annamaria. Other Signs, Other Circles: A Selection of Poems, 1990-2009 (translated by Anamaría Crowe Serrano), 2009, undated; 10 (Box 64)
    - Gatto, Alfonso. The Wall Did Not Answer: Selected Poems, 1932-1976 (translated by Philip Parisi), 2009; 3 (Box 64)
  - Other Papers
    - Printed material, 2002-2008 (Box 64)
- August 2010 Acquisition, 2006-2010; 1.42; (3 boxes)
  - Correspondence
    - Unsorted, 2009-2010; 2 (Box 66)
  - Chelsea Editions Publications
    - Ferramosca, Annamaria. Other Signs, Other Circles: A Selection of Poems, 1990-2009 (translated by Anamaría Crowe Serrano), undated; 2 CDs (Box 66)
    - Neri, Giampiero. Natural Theater: Selected Poems, 1976-2009 (translated by Ron Banerjee), 2010; 5 (Box 66)
    - Spaziani, Maria Luisa. Painted Fire: A Selection of Poems, 1954-2006 (translated by Lynne Lawner), 2006-2010, undated; 11 folders, including 2 CDs (Box 66)
  - Literary Prizes
    - Raiziss/de Palchi Translation Awards (applications), 2008-2009; 12 (Box 66)
  - Other Papers
    - Printed material, 2009, undated; 2 (Box 67)
    - Manuscripts removed from books (Box 67)
- January 2011 Acquisition
  - Correspondence
    - Unsorted, 2008-2010; 3 (Box 75)
  - Chelsea Editions Publications
    - Gatto, Alfonso. The Wall Did Not Answer: Selected Poems, 1932-1976 (translated by Philip Parisi), 2010; 6 (Box 75)
  - Other Writings
    - De Palchi, Alfredo. Paradigm: New and Selected Poems, 1947-2009 (edited by John Taylor) (correspondence), 2009-2010; 4 (Box 75)
    - De Palchi, Alfredo. Paradigm: New and Selected Poems, 1947-2009 (edited by John Taylor) (drafts), 4 (Box 75)
  - Other Papers
    - Printed material (Box 75)
- November 2012 Acquisition, 1993-2012; 3.21; (4 boxes)
  - Correspondence
    - Unsorted, 2009-2012; 8 (Box 69)
  - Chelsea Editions Publications
    - "Chelsea Editions Publications: Modern and Contemporary Italian Poetry in Translation" (event, 2011 April 5), 2010-2011; 2 (Box 69)
    - Dante Alighieri. Vita nuova (translated by Emanuel di Pasquale), 2004-2009; 9 folders, including 2 3.5 inch disks (Box 69)
    - Fantato, Gabriela. Form of Life: New and Selected Poems, 1996-2009 (translated by Emanuel di Pasquale), 2010-2012, undated; 5 (Box 69)
    - Jaccottet, Philippe. And, Nonetheless: Selected Prose and Poetry, 1990-2009 (translated by John Taylor), undated (Box 69)
    - Jourdan, Pierre-Albert. The Straw Sandals: Selected Prose and Poetry (translated by John Taylor), 2010-2011, undated; 3 (Box 69)
    - Rosselli, Amelia. The Dragonfly: A Selection of Poems, 1953-1981 (translated by Deborah Woodard), 2008-2010 (Box 70)
  - Other Writings
    - de Palchi, Alfredo. Dalla nebbia, 2008 (Box 70)
    - de Palchi, Alfredo. Foemina tellus, undated (Box 70)
    - de Palchi, Alfredo. Paradigm: New and Selected Poems, 1947-2009 (edited by John Taylor), 2009-2010 (Box 70)
    - Linguaglossa, Giorgio. La nuova poesia modernista italiana (EdiLet), 2010, undated; 6 (Box 70)
    - Phillips, Rowan Ricardo. Poems, 2008 (Box 70)
  - Literary Prizes
    - Fondazione Vittorio e Piero Alinari Poetry Prize, 2011 (printed material) (Box 70)
    - Fondazione Vittorio e Piero Alinari Poetry Prize, 2011 (applications), 29 folders, including 1 CD (Box 70)
    - Raiziss/de Palchi Translation Awards (applications), 2011; 19 (Box 71)
  - Other Papers
    - Printed material, 2009 (Box 71)
    - New York State Council on the Arts grants, 1993-2003, undated; 4 (Box 71)
    - Computer equipment documentation, undated; 1 folder, including 7 CDs (Box 71)
    - Unidentified, 2010, undated (Box 71)
- May 2013 Acquisition, 1998-2013; 1.25; (2 boxes)
  - Correspondence
    - Unsorted, 2012; 3 (Box 73)
  - Chelsea Issues
    - Chelsea 54-68, 70/71 (1993-2001), 1 3.5 inch disk and 14 zip disks (Box 73)
    - Chelsea (unidentified issues), 45 3.5 inch disks (Box 73)
  - Chelsea Editions Publications
    - Calaferte, Louis. The Violet Blood of the Amethyst (translated by John Taylor), 1998-2013; 3 (Box 73)
    - de Palchi, Alfred. Paradigm: New and Selected Poems, 1947-2009 (translated by John Taylor), 2010-2011, undated; 4 folders, including 1 CD (Box 73)
    - Fantato, Gabriela. The Form of Life: New and Selected Poems, 1996-2009 (translated by Emanuel de Pasquale), undated; 3 (Box 73)
  - Other Writings
    - Kinzie Bastian, Rebecca Charms for Finding (translated by Elisa Biagini) (Mimesis Edizioni), 2012, undated; 4 (Box 73)
  - Other Papers
    - Administrative files, 14 3.5 inch disks (Box 73)